<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Answers at the End</title>
    <link>https://NicknEma.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Answers at the End</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 16:43:01 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://NicknEma.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Infinity of Lines and Numbers</title>
      <link>https://NicknEma.github.io/posts/the-infinity-of-lines-and-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 16:43:01 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://NicknEma.github.io/posts/the-infinity-of-lines-and-numbers/</guid>
      <description>“Young man, in mathematics you don&amp;rsquo;t understand things. You just get used to them.”&#xA;– John von Neumann&#xA;This is a line:&#xA;I was introduced to this mathematical object when I was in elementary school. The teacher drew one on the blackboard, and then said &amp;ldquo;a line is composed of an infinite number of points. The dashes at the ends indicate that it continues on forever, in both directions&amp;rdquo;. At first, I was surprised by the mention of infinity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Equality and the reunion of broken parts</title>
      <link>https://NicknEma.github.io/posts/equality-and-the-reunion-of-broken-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 23:27:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://NicknEma.github.io/posts/equality-and-the-reunion-of-broken-parts/</guid>
      <description>We are used to think that the word &amp;ldquo;equals&amp;rdquo; means something very specific in mathematics. I can put an operation on the left side of the page, like this:&#xA;\[2 + 2\] And then I can ask you what this is equal to:&#xA;\[2 + 2 =\] That symbol, called the &amp;ldquo;equal sign&amp;rdquo;, is treated like a question mark. What is on its left forms a question, and then you put your answer on the right.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lies, Secrets and Multiplexers</title>
      <link>https://NicknEma.github.io/posts/lies-secrets-and-multiplexers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 19:26:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://NicknEma.github.io/posts/lies-secrets-and-multiplexers/</guid>
      <description>You are on a street, one person coming towards you from your right, another from your left. You know that, when they will have reached you, one of them will tell the truth and one will lie. To know which one will do what, you only need the answer to one yes-or-no question; in computer terms, you need 1 bit of information to choose which person to trust. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you ask &amp;ldquo;should I trust the person coming from the right?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
